Labor Action Coalition Records 6092
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Labor Action Coalition Records
1962-1988
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Labor Action Coalition
6092
5.11 cubic feet
4.1 linear ft.
Records.
5794413
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 06, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 19, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6092 AV: Labor Action Coalition Audio-Visual Material 6092 MB: Labor Action Coalition Memorabilia
Labor Acition Coalition
5794413
- Jinx Dowd, Resume (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Resume of Virginia Dowd
- Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Long Island Progressive Alliance Newsletters (Marge Harrison), 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Carol Bernstein Ferry, Fundraising, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dan Leaky, Letters to "Jinx" Dowd, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Contains two photographs
- Ed Bloch, 1982-1983 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ed Barkley, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Primarily correspondence with Virginia Dowd
- Ed Barkley, 1981, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Ed Barkley, 1982 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Ed Barkley, Continued 1983 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ed Barkley, 1984-1985 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Labor Action Coalition Executive Board List, 1984, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Labor Action Coalition, 1984, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Sixth Annual Legislative Conference, Albany, NY Photographs, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  May 1981; Contains 27 photographs
- Sixth Annual Legislative Conference, Albany, New York, Photographs, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  May, 1981; contains around 50 photographs
- Labor Action Coalition Annual Reports, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Labor Action Coalition Conference, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Labor Action Coalition Rally Report, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Labor Action Coalition Annual Report 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Sixth Annual Legislative Conference, Albany, New York, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  March 1 - 3, 1981
- Copy for Conference Report and Pictures, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  March 1979; Contains 3 photographs
- Resolutions, Labor Action Coalition, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Labor Action Coalition Registration Lists, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Human Affairs Program, Community Organizing Manual (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Press Releases, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Utilities: Preference Question and Answer and CWIP, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Labor Action Coalition Brochure, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Western New York Coalition for Jobs, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  425 Military Road, Buffalo, New York, 14207
- 7103-D "Right to Know", 1980 Passed Assembly and Senate, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Public Service Announcement: Elderly Project, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Labor Action Coalition Continuation Committee Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- The Plane Report: Cornell's Land Grant Mission, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Endorsement of Candidates, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Political Advocacy and Activism of Virginia Dowd and Others, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous Labor Action Coalition Documents regarding Utilities, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Report of Labor Action Conference on Public Utilities, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Liverpool, New York; November 8 - 9, 1975
- "Phantom Taxes in your Electric Bill", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Environmental Action Foundation
- "How to Challenge your Local Electric Utility: A Citizen's Guide to the Power Industry", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "Taking Charge: A New Look at Public Power", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "Questions and Answers on Public Power", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  People's Power Coalition of New York State; January 1978
- "People's Energy: A No Nukes/ Sane Energy 1979 Calendar" (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Calendar
- "Exploratory Project for Economic Alternatives: Understanding the New Inflation: The Importance of Basic Necessities", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "Open the Books: How to research a Corporation", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- "The Price of Power: Electric Utilities and the Environment", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  The Council on Economic Priorities
- "Public Power: In the Best Tradition of American Enterprise", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- "The National Fuel Gas Story: An Unauthorized Report", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Buffalo New American Movement Utilities Project
- "A Working Economy for Americans", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Americans for a Working Economy
- "CDE Stock Ownership Directory: Energy", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Corporate Data Exchange, Inc.
- "The People's Right to Choose", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- "An Introduction to Public Power: There is an Alternative to Lilco" (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Long Island Public Power Project
- "Private Power and Public Service: A Proposal to Restructure the Public Service Commission", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  March 1982
- "The New-Right", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Prepared for the Twenty-Third Annual Statewide USWA Legislative Conference by Paul F. Clark, Department of Labor Studies, Pennsylvania State University
- "A Citizen's Guide to the Fuel Adjustment Clause", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Environmental Action Foundation; August 1975
- "An Organizer's Notebook on Public Utilities and Energy for New York State", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Public Utilities/Energy Project, Human Affairs Program, Cornell University
- Information from NY Power Pool, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Contains various reports on the state of energy in New York
- Information on Local Publicly Owned Electric Utilities, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  American Public Power Association; contains various documents on public power
- The Public Benefits of Public Power, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  American Public Power Association
- "Time to Choose" State Action Conference on Municipal Power, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Upstate Community Resource Institute; April 23 - 25, 1976
- 'Environmentalists for Full Employment" Pamphlet, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Berkshire Forum Weekend Vacation Workshops, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Summer 1988
- "Taking Charge: A New Look at Public Power", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- "Nuclear Power: The Bargain We Can't Afford", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- "Interlocking Directorates Among the Major U.S. Corporations", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  A staff Study Prepared by the Subcommittee on Reports, Accounting and Management of the Committee on Governmental Affairs United States Senate; January 1978
- Nuclear Energy, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Newsletters and Factsheets on nuclear Energy
- "The Impact of Military Spending on the Machinists Union", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  January 1979
- "Jobs and Energy", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  Environmentalists for Full Employment; Spring 1977
- "Plant Closings: Issues, Politics and Legislation", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Briefing Book, Economic Development Project, Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies; December 1980
- Industrial Health and Safety, 1963-1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Correspondence and Reports Concerning Toxic Substances, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "The Right to Know Law: What You Should Know About Toxic Substances", 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Bureau of Toxic Substances Assessment, NY State Health Department
- "The Right to Know Law: What You Should Know About Toxic Substances", 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  New York State Health department; Contains the Assembly bill and a public awareness poster
- Factsheets and Bulletins on Toxic Substances, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Training Materials on Toxic Substances: Tools for Effective Action Book 2, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Sierra Club; January 1981
- Training Materials on Toxic Substances: Tools for Effective Action Book 1, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ny State Department of Health 1986 Chemical Factsheet Collection (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Toxic Substances: First Aid Information (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Toxic Substances: First Aid Information, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Toxic Substances: First Aid Information, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Binder A, Documents Regarding Energy and Toxic Substances Activism, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Binder B, Part 1, Operating Details of the Labor Action Coalition and Legislative Proposals, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Binder B, Part 2, Conference Documents, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Binder B, Part 3, Letters, Endorsements, and Energy Documents, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Labor Action Coalition Information Sheets for the Right to Know Law, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Labor Action Coalition of New York, Miscellaneous Documents, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Labor Action Coalition of New York, Toxic Substances, Power and Miscellaneous Documents, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Labor Action Coalition of New York, Miscellaneous Documents, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Labor Action Coalition of New York, Miscellaneous Documents, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Labor Action Coalition Nuclear Energy Documents, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Labor Action Coalition Public Utilities Documents, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Labor Action Coalition Municipal Power Documents, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Power Line Weekend, Holland Patent, NY, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  February 4 - 6, 1977
- Labor Action Coalition of New York, Nuclear Energy, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- "Municipal Power for NY State", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  A State Action Conference; April 23 - 25, 1976
- Labor Action Coalition of New York, Public Power, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Labor Action Coalition of New York, Gas Supply, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Labor Action Conference on Public Utilities, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Conference Binder D, Part 1, Opposition to 765 KV Lines, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Conference Binder D, Part 2, "Accidents", 1962-1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Conference Binder D, Part 3, Accidents and Incidents, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Conference Binder C, Part 1, Nuclear Power Information, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Conference Binder C, Part 2, Nuclear Waste, Siting and Uranium Mining, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Conference Binder E, Part 1, Phantom Taxes, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Conference Binder E, Part 2, NY Towns' Responses to Power, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Conference Binder E, Part 3, Ny Towns' Responses to Energy, Information on Power Companies, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Ronald Reagan Film Poster, Organization Poster, Labor Action Coalition Poster (Box 5)